Alexander Petrunkevitch Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
Alexander Petrunkevitch Archives
1909-1964
ENTAR.001825
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
5
The archives of Alexander Petrunkevitch, accumulated during his time at Yale.
Petrunkevitch, Alexander, 1875-1964
Biographical Sketch
Born in Russia, moved to germany for PhD (1900). Became professor of Zooloogy at Yale. Made man contributions to the field of Arachnids.
Description of the Material
The Archives of Alexander Petrunkevitch include correspondence, manuscript and biographical materials as well as Yale lecture materials.
Germany; USA; Correspondence; Yale Peabody Museum; Yale University
- Correspondence, Series I
  - Abbott, Clinton G. EST number of items 10+., 1944-1945; 001827
  - Abraham, H.C. EST number of items 15+., 1923-1931; 001828
  - Acharji, M.N. EST number of items = 1., 1954; 001829
  - Adams, L.A. EST number of items = 3., 1947; 001830
  - Albritton, E.C. EST number of items=5., 1950-1952; 001831
  - Alden, Roland H. EST number of items= 1., 1944; 001832
  - Aldrich, H.R. EST number of items= 5., 1949-1951; 001833
  - Alexander, Charles P. EST number of items= 5., 1950-1957; 001834
  - Alexander, Mary D. EST number of items= 1., 1954; 001835
  - Allen, Elsa G. EST number of items= 3., 1955; 001836
  - Altena, C.O.van Regteren. EST number of items= 10+., 1949-1954; 001837
  - American Philosophical Society. EST number of items= 25+., 1934-1950; 001838
  - Anderson, F.E. EST number of items= 2., 1949-1950; 001839
  - Andree, Karl D. EST number of items= 5+., 1950-1952; 001840
  - Andrews, E.A. EST number of items= 2., 1947; 001841
  - Andrews, Warren. EST number of items= 2., 1950-1958; 001842
  - Archer, Allan. EST number of items= 10+., 1944-1950; 001843
  - Archey, Gilbert. EST number of items= 5+., 1929-1952; 001844
  - Arroyo, Miguel A. EST number of items= 1., 1944; 001845
  - Ashlock, Peter D. EST number of items= 2., 1963; 001846
  - Atkinson, William B. EST number of items= 1., 1946; 001847
  - Atwater, R.M. EST number of items= 1., 1952; 001848
  - Augusta, Josef. EST number of items= 1., 1937; 001849
  - Baerg, W.J. EST number of items = 5+., 1923-1952; 001878
  - Bahl, K.N. EST number of items = 5+., 1942-1952; 001879
  - Baitsell, George A. EST number of items = 2., 1956; 001880
  - Ball, John R. EST number of items = 1., 1949; 001882
  - Banks, Nathen. EST number of items = 5., 1909-1925; 001883
  - Barnard, K.A. EST number of items = 2., 1942-1949; 001884
  - Barrett, Charles. EST number of items = 2., 1931; 001885
  - Barros, Octavio. EST number of items = 2., 1946; 001886
  - Barrows, W.M. EST number of items = 5+., 1928-1930; 001887
  - Barry, John J. EST number of items = 3., 1953; 001888
  - Bassindale, R. EST number of items = 3., 1947; 001889
  - Bassler, R.S. EST number of items = 5+., 1946-1949; 001890
  - Bausch & Lomb Optical Company., 1947; 001891
  - Beattie, John O., 1953; 001892
  - Bee. Date and first initial unknown., 001893
  - Bell-Marley, H., 1944-1945; 001894
  - Berland, M.L. EST number of items= 5+., 1913-1962; 001895
  - Bishop, S.C. EST number of items= 2., 1945; 001896
  - Blauvelt, H.H. EST number of items= 1., 1938; 001898
  - Bledsoe, Lucy. EST number of items= 2., 1952; 001899
  - Bode-Bodey, E. EST number of items= 1., 1950; 001900
  - Boisen Bennikie, S.A. EST number of items= 1., 1939; 001901
  - Bonnet, P. EST number of items= 15+., 1927-1947; 001902
  - Boyden, Alan. EST number of items = 1., 1949; 002363
  - Brady, L.F. EST number of items= 10+., 1940-1952; 001907
  - Braendegard, Jens. EST number of items= 5., 1929-1951; 001908
  - Braniff, Edward. EST number of items= 2., 1950; 001909
  - Breneman, W.R. EST number of items= 1., 1947; 001910
  - Brien, Paul. EST number of items= 2., 1946-1950; 001911
  - Brighton, A. G. EST number of items= 10+., 1935-1950; 001912
  - Bristowe, W.S. EST number of items= 10+., 1927-1944; 001913
  - Britsh Museum, Dept of Geology. EST number of items = 25+., 1934-1955; 001881
  - Brooks, Harold K. EST number of items= 2., 1952; 001914
  - Brooks, Paul. EST number of items= 5+., 1950-1951; 001915
  - Brown, Frank. EST number of items= 1., 1949; 001916
  - Brown, Relis. EST number of items= 2., 1944-1950; 001917
  - Browning, E. EST number of items= 5., 1949-1950; 001918
  - Bruce, Norval S. EST number of items= 1., 1947; 001919
  - Brues, Charles T. EST number of items= 1., 1940; 001920
  - Bruun, Anton. EST number of items= 1., 1939; 001921
  - Bryan, Edwin H. EST number of items= 2., 1948-1950; 001922
  - Bryant, Elizabeth. EST number of items= 25+., 1932-1945; 001923
  - Buchanan, Thomas S. EST number of items= 2., 1946; 001924
  - Buck, John B. EST number of items= 1., 1951; 001925
  - Buecherl, Wolfgang. EST number of items= 1., 1949; 001926
  - Bueno, J.R. EST number of items= 1., 1924; 001927
  - Burfeind, Nat T. EST number of items= 1., 1945; 001928
  - Burfield, Stanley T. EST number of items= 5+., 1931; 001929
  - Burnside, John L. EST number of items= 1., 1950; 001930
  - Butler, Stanley. EST number of items= 5., 1928-1931; 001931
  - Camp, Charles. EST number of items= 1., 1949; 001932
  - Campbell, George R. EST number of items= 2., 1942-1952; 001933
  - Canals, Jose. EST number of items= 5+., 1929-1942; 001934
  - Carmen, G. EST number of items = 1., 1922; 002366
  - Carpenter, F.M. EST number of items= 15+., 1946-1952; 001935
  - Carter, Phyllis. EST number of items= 2., 1952; 001936
  - Casavilca, A. R. EST number of items= 1., 1963; 001937
  - Cattell, J.M. EST number of items= 5., 1919-1920; 001938
  - Cattoi, Noemi. EST number of items= 2., 1949-1950; 001939
  - Chaitonov, D.E. EST number of items = 3., 1926-1930; 002365
  - Chamberlin, R.V. EST number of items=10+., 1909-1944; 001940
  - Chapin, E.A. EST number of items= 3., 1949; 001941
  - Chardon, Carlos E. EST number of items=1., 1949; 001942
  - Chickering, A.M. EST number of items=15+., 1933-1952; 001943
  - Chrystal, Charlotte. EST number of items=3., 1924; 001944
  - Clarke, Angus W. EST number of items=3., 1950-1951; 001945
  - Cloudsley-Thompson. EST number of items= 5 +., 1948-1952; 001946
  - Cobb, N.A. EST number of items= 2., 1921-1922; 001947
  - Cockerell, Theo D.A. EST number of items= 5+., 1922-1936; 001948
  - Collins, E.D. EST number of items= 1., 001949
  - Conklin, E.G. EST number of items= 3., 1937-1942; 001950
  - Cooper, G.A. EST number of items= 5+., 1946-1951; 001951
  - Cooper, Kenneth W. EST number of items = 5+., 1943-1950; 001952
  - Cooreman, J. EST number of items = 2., 1949; 001953
  - Copeland, Murray J. EST number of items = 2., 1952; 001954
  - Cory, E.N. EST number of items = 2., 1953; 001955
  - Cox, A.H. EST number of items = 1., 1949; 001956
  - Craig, Patrick R. EST number of items = 1., 1961; 001957
  - Crampton, G.C. EST number of items = 2., 1923-1935; 001958
  - Crampton, John. EST number of items = 1., 1950; 001959
  - Crane, Jocelyn. EST number of items = 10+., 1943-1947; 001960
  - Croly, John T. EST number of items = 1., 1963; 001961
  - Crosby, C.R. EST number of items = 5., 1922-1927; 001962
  - Crowell, Robert L. EST number of items = 3., 1952; 001963
  - Curtiss, Anthony. EST number of items = 1., 1951; 001964
  - Dalcq, A.M. EST number of items = 2., 1949; 001965
  - Dalmas. EST number of items = 3., 1920-1928; 001966
  - Dampf, Alfonso. EST number of items = 5., 1926-1933; 001967
  - Darlington, P.J. EST number of items = 3., 1953; 001968
  - Davidson, E.A. EST number of items = 1., 1957; 001969
  - Day, G.P. EST number of items = 1., 1953; 001970
  - Debaisieux, Paul. EST number of items = 3., 1949-1950; 001971
  - Deevey, G. EST number of items = 3., 1950; 001972
  - Denis, Jacques. EST number of items = 2., 1932; 001975
  - Deuel, Thorne. EST number of items = 15+., 1945-1949; 001973
  - Dexter, John S. EST number of items = 3., 1929; 001974
  - Dias Da Rocha. EST number of items = 3., 1941-1946; 002364
  - Doering, Kay. EST number of items = 2., 1948; 001976
  - Dogiel, V. EST number of items = 1., 1943; 001977
  - Doob, Leonard. EST number of items = 1., 1964; 001978
  - Dozier, H.L. EST number of items = 1., 1930; 001979
  - Dragesco, Jean. EST number of items = 1., 1950; 001980
  - Drensky, P. EST number of items = 1., 1948; 001981
  - Dukes, W.C. EST number of items = 2., 1920; 001982
  - Dunbar, Carl. EST number of items = 1., 1945; 001983
  - Duncan, Winifred. EST number of items = 3., 1949; 001984
  - Dunn, L.C. EST number of items = 3., 1952; 001985
  - Duyvene de Wit, J.J. EST number of items = 1., 1953; 002355
  - Eagar, R.H.C. EST number of items = 1., 1953; 001986
  - Eaton, George F. EST number of items = 1., 1925; 001987
  - Eddy, Brayton. EST number of items = 1., 1947; 001988
  - Elias, M.K. EST number of items = 2., 1949-1951; 001989
  - Elishewitz, H. EST number of items = 1., 1953; 001990
  - Elkin, D.C. EST number of items = 1., 1950; 001991
  - Ellis, C.H. EST number of items = 1., 1944; 001992
  - Emans, Elaine V. EST number of items = 1., 001993
  - Emerit, Michel. EST number of items = 1., 1963; 001994
  - Emerton, J. H. EST number of items = 10+., 1924-1929; 001995
  - Encyclopedia Britannica. EST number of items = 20+., 1944-1959; 001996
  - Erhart, H. EST number of items = 2., 1944; 001997
  - Essig, E.O. EST number of items = 3., 1928; 001998
  - Evans, Howard E. EST number of items = 2., 1952; 001999
  - Evitt, W.R. EST number of items = 2., 1956; 002000
  - Ewing, H.E. EST number of items = 3., 1929; 002001
  - Fage, Louis. EST number of items = 20+., 1923-1949; 002003
  - Fang, P.W. EST number of items = 2., 1927; 002004
  - Faunce, W.M. EST number of items = 2., 1947-1952; 002005
  - Feath, Jaclyn. EST number of items = 2., 1961-1962; 002002
  - Feio, A. EST number of items = 2., 1949; 002006
  - Finnegan, Susan. EST number of items = 15+., 1932-1934; 002007
  - Fischel, Werner. EST number of items = 5., 1927; 002008
  - Fischelis, Philipp. EST number of items = 1., 1922; 002009
  - Fisher, J.W. EST number of items = 1., 1945; 002010
  - Fitch, Leslie A. EST number of items = 2., 1950; 002011
  - Flynn, John E. EST number of items = 1., 1949; 002015
  - Forster, R.R. EST number of items = 5+., 1950-1954; 002012
  - Franganillo, Pelegrin. EST number of items = 3., 1929-1939; 002013
  - French, Robert D. EST number of items = 1., 1946; 002014
  - Friend, Roger B. EST number of items = 1., 1947; 002016
  - Fritz, M.A. EST number of items = 10+., 1950-1953; 002017
  - Frizzell, Harriet. EST number of items = 40+. A large amount of this correspondence refers to the death of A. Petrunkevitch., 1942-1964; 002018
  - Gardiner, Leroy V. EST number of items = 1., 1924; 002019
  - Gardiner, Mary S. EST number of items = 1., 1954; 002020
  - Gatenby, Bronte. EST number of items = 2., 1947; 002021
  - Gaw, H.Z. EST number of items = 2., 1939; 002022
  - Gerhardt, Ulrich. EST number of items = 15+., 1926-1932; 002023
  - Gering, Robert L. EST number of items = 10+., 1952; 002024
  - Gersbacher, W.M. EST number of items = 1., 1951; 002025
  - Gerschman, Berta S. EST number of items = 4., 1940; 002026
  - Gertsch, W.J. EST number of items = 20+., 1930-1954; 002027
  - Getmanov, V. EST number of items = 5+., 1950; 002028
  - Gillman, Theodore. EST number of items = 1., 1936; 002029
  - Giltay, Louis. EST number of items = 5+., 1928-1933; 002030
  - Goldring, Winifred. EST number of items = 2., 1949-1950; 002031
  - Goldschmidt, R.B. EST number of items = 5+., 1948-1954; 002032
  - Goodenough, Erwin R. EST number of items = 2., 1948; 002033
  - Goodnight, Clarence. EST number of items = 15+., 1946-1953; 002036
  - Goutiere, M.C. EST number of items = 2., 1944; 002034
  - Gregory, H.E. EST number of items = 1., 1920; 002035
  - Griscom, Ludlow. EST number of items = 1., 1949; 002037
  - Guild, W. EST number of items = 1., 1950; 002038
  - Guthorl, P. EST number of items = 5., 1952-1953; 002039
  - Guzman, L.E. EST number of items = 1., 002040
  - Hadzi, J. EST number of items = 5+., 1948-1957; 002043
  - Hamburger, Clara. EST number of items = 5+., 002044
  - Hamilton, John M. EST number of items = 1., 1952; 002045
  - Hancock, Richard. EST number of items = 10+., 1925-1934; 002046
  - Hanson, John F. EST number of items = 1., 1949; 002047
  - Hantzschel, W. EST number of items = 1., 1956; 002048
  - Hargis, William J. EST number of items = 1., 1952; 002049
  - Harris, C. EST number of items = 1., 1947; 002050
  - Hartman, Carl G. EST number of items = 2., 1952; 002051
  - Harvey, Newton E. EST number of items = 1., 1953; 002055
  - Hase, A. EST number of items = 1., 1929; 002052
  - Haseman, L. EST number of items = 1., 1946; 002053
  - Hass, Otto H. EST number of items = 5+., 1946-1949; 002041
  - Hassan, A.I. EST number of items = 5+., 1947-1948; 002042
  - Hausman, L.A. EST number of items = 10+., 1937-1947; 002054
  - Hedgepeth, J.W. EST number of items = 10+., 1949-1961; 002057
  - Heegaard, Poul E. EST number of items = 3., 1949-1952; 002056
  - Heide, S. EST number of items = 1., 1950; 002058
  - Hellmich, Walter. EST number of items = 1., 1931; 002059
  - Hendel, Charles W. EST number of items = 3., 1948; 002061
  - Hendiksen, Kai L. EST number of items = 2., 1927; 002062
  - Hermann, G. EST number of items = 3., 1937; 002063
  - Hesse, E. EST number of items = 2., 1932; 002064
  - Hewitt, John. EST number of items = 1., 1923; 002065
  - Hewlett, E.P. EST number of items = 1., 1945; 002066
  - Hickman, V.V. EST number of items = 25+., 1923-1954; 002067
  - Hindle, Edward. EST number of items = 1., 1949; 002068
  - Hingston, R. EST number of items = 3., 1930; 002069
  - Hoffmann, Carlos C. EST number of items = 1., 1933; 002070
  - Homann, H. EST number of items = 5+., 1928-1952; 002071
  - Houssay, B.A. EST number of items = 1., 1940; 002072
  - Howard, L.O. EST number of items = 10+., 1920-1930; 002073
  - Howell, B. EST number of items = 1., 1949; 002074
  - Huey, L.M. EST number of items = 2., 1947; 002075
  - Huntington, Ellsworth. EST number of items = 1., 1945; 002076
  - Hutchins, Louis W. EST number of items = 1., 1948; 002077
  - Ince, A.S. EST number of items = 1., 1953; 002078
  - Indiana University. EST number of items = 2., 1951; 002079
  - Inomata, S. EST number of items = 2., 1928; 002080
  - International Commission on Zoological Nomenclature. EST number of items = 5+., 1955-1958; 002060
  - Ipsen. EST number of items = 10+., 1949; 002081
  - Ishikawa, C. EST number of items = 1., 1927; 002082
  - Ivie, Wilton. EST number of items = 1., 1933; 002083
  - Jackson. EST number of items = 3., 002084
  - Jacot, Aurthur P. EST number of items = 2., 1930-1933; 002085
  - Jahn, T.L. EST number of items = 2., 1952; 002086
  - Janer, W.M. EST number of items = 1., 1946; 002088
  - Jennings, H.S. EST number of items = 1., 1928; 002087
  - Jirovec, Otto. EST number of items = 3., 1949; 002089
  - Jones, Robert F. EST number of items = 1., 1945; 002090
  - Jorgensen, Harriet. EST number of items = 2., 1950-1952; 002091
  - Justice, John R. EST number of items = 2., 1944; 002092
  - Kaestner, A. EST number of items = 5+., 1950-1957; 002106
  - Kellogg, R. EST number of items = 3., 1951; 002107
  - Kerr, Ruth. EST number of items = 1., 1949; 002108
  - Khanamirian, A. EST number of items = 1., 1949; 002109
  - Kiil, V. EST number of items = 2., 1948-1949; 002110
  - Kinkead, E. EST number of items = 2., 1948; 002111
  - Kolosvary, G. EST number of items = 2., 002112
  - Kopp, A. EST number of items = 1., 1925; 002113
  - Koroleff, A. EST number of items = 1., 1951; 002114
  - Kousnetzoff, W. EST number of items = 5+., 1932; 002115
  - Kozlowski, Roman. EST number of items = 2+., 1954-1959; 002116
  - Kratochvil, J. EST number of items = 1., 1948; 002118
  - Krizenecky, J. EST number of items = 1., 1963; 002117
  - Kummel, B. EST number of items = 5+., 1953-1954; 002119
  - Ladd, H.S. EST number of items = 2., 1954; 002120
  - Laisne, G. EST number of items = 3., 1929; 002121
  - Lane, Frank. EST number of items = 3., 1954; 002122
  - Lang, Marshall. EST number of items = 1., 1944; 002123
  - Langford, George. EST number of items = 5+., 1945-1953; 002124
  - Larsson, G. EST number of items = 3., 1951-1957; 002125
  - Laveu, H. EST number of items = 2., 1952; 002126
  - Lawrence, R. EST number of items = 10+., 1928-1949; 002127
  - Lawson, John. EST number of items = 1., 1950; 002128
  - Legendre, R. EST number of items = 1., 1953; 002129
  - Lehmann, W.M. EST number of items = 5+., 1950-1954; 002130
  - Lenard, M.D. EST number of items = 1., 1930; 002131
  - Lessark, R.D. EST number of items = 5+., 1924-1938; 002360
  - Leuffer, Herman C. EST number of items = 5., 1944; 002132
  - Levi, H. EST number of items = 2., 1950-1951; 002133
  - Lloyd, F.E. EST number of items = 5+., 1944; 002134
  - Lokietz, Norman. EST number of items = 1., 002135
  - Lonnfors, Frans. EST number of items = 1., 1949; 002136
  - Lord, Frank. EST number of items = 1., 002137
  - Lowenstam, Heinz. EST number of items = 3., 1343; 002138
  - Lowrie, Donald C. EST number of items = 5+., 1938-1951; 002139
  - Machodo, A. EST number of items = 10+., 1944-1952; 002140
  - Mainarde, Athos. EST number of items = 1., 1930; 002141
  - Marcus, E. EST number of items = 3., 1949-1950; 002142
  - Marcus, H. EST number of items = 5+., 1945-1949; 002143
  - Marples, B.J. EST number of items = 1., 1949; 002144
  - Mathewson, John A. EST number of items = 1., 1952; 002145
  - Mathias, J.F. EST number of items = 1., 1951; 002146
  - Mayne, R. EST number of items = 2., 1955; 002147
  - Mayr, E. EST number of items = 1., 1952; 002148
  - McGregor, John C. EST number of items = 5., 1945; 002149
  - McKee, Edwin D. EST number of items = 5+., 1944-1949; 002150
  - Mello-Leitao,. EST number of items = 10+., 1922-1949; 002151
  - Mendes, E. EST number of items = 2., 1947; 002152
  - Mendezabol, Hugo. EST number of items = 2., 1942; 002153
  - Merriam, John C. EST number of items = 5., 1922-1923; 002154
  - Meyer, Marvin C. EST number of items = 2., 1949; 002155
  - Miller, J.S. EST number of items = 5+., 1951; 002156
  - Millot, J. EST number of items = 5+., 1930-1947; 002157
  - Miner, I.O. EST number of items = 1., 1950; 002158
  - Miroyiannis, Stanley D. EST number of items = 2., 1946; 002159
  - Mitchell, Roger D. EST number of items = 2., 1952; 002160
  - Miyajima, M. EST number of items = 3., 1922-1927; 002362
  - Moment, G.B. EST number of items = 2., 1955; 002161
  - Montgomery, R.H. EST number of items = 1., 1944; 002162
  - Moomaw, D. EST number of items = 1., 1945; 002163
  - Moore, Raymond C. EST number of items = 20+., 1949-1955; 002164
  - Morehouse, T.C. EST number of items = 2., 1946; 002165
  - Moreno, A. EST number of items = 1., 1945; 002166
  - Muma, Martin H. EST number of items = 3., 1947-1953; 002167
  - Mumford, E.P. EST number of items = 1., 1934; 002168
  - Nakastuji, K. EST number of items = 1., 1926; 002361
  - National Academy of Sciences. EST number of items = 10+., 1954; 002169
  - National Geographical Society. EST number of items = 20+., 1923-1923; 002260
  - Natvig, L.R. EST number of items = 5., 1929; 002170
  - Newell, Norman D. EST number of items = 3., 1947-1948; 002171
  - Nicholas, John S. EST number of items = 4., 1956; 002173
  - Nicholls, G. EST number of items = 1., 1945; 002174
  - Nichols, Ray J. EST number of items = 2., 1928; 002175
  - Nielson, Eigil. EST number of items = 10+., 1949-1957; 002172
  - Norton, Anna S. EST number of items = 2., 1944; 002176
  - Novikoff, M. EST number of items = 1., 1950; 002177
  - O'Connor, Timothy. EST number of items = 2., 1954; 002178
  - Odum, Howard T. EST number of items = 1., 1950; 002179
  - Olsoufieff, G. EST number of items = 5+., 1931-1933; 002180
  - Oosterhout, G.W. EST number of items = 2., 1954; 002181
  - Ortiz, Cesar R. EST number of items = 1., 1942; 002182
  - Painter, T.S. EST number of items = 5+., 1938-1949; 002183
  - Palmer, Allison R. EST number of items = 10+., 1954-1957; 002184
  - Parish, H.G. EST number of items = 1., 1950; 002187
  - Park, Thomas. EST number of items = 2., 1947; 002185
  - Parker, H.L. EST number of items = 3., 1950-1963; 002186
  - Parrot, A.W. EST number of items = 2., 1931-1947; 002188
  - Parsons, Carl T. EST number of items = 1., 1950; 002189
  - Passmore, Lee. EST number of items = 2., 1940; 002190
  - Pavlovsky, E.N. EST number of items = 3., 1914; 002191
  - Peabody, Frank E. EST number of items = 2., 1953; 002192
  - Pearce, W.M. EST number of items = 2., 1947; 002193
  - Pearse, A.S. EST number of items = 3., 1947-1950; 002194
  - Peelle, M.L. EST number of items = 1., 1932; 002195
  - Peters, Hans. EST number of items = 1., 1939; 002196
  - Petrusewicz, K. EST number of items = 1., 002197
  - Pickford, G.E. EST number of items = 4., 1949-1965; 002198
  - Pickford, R.W. EST number of items = 3., 1946-1949; 002199
  - Pieltain, B.C. EST number of items = 2., 1941; 002200
  - Pinkus, L.F. EST number of items = 3., 1928-1954; 002201
  - Pittendrigh, C.S. EST number of items = 2., 1952; 002202
  - Plough, Harold H. EST number of items = 5+., 1950; 002203
  - Popoff, G. EST number of items = 5+., 1950; 002204
  - Porter, C.E. EST number of items = 3., 1925-1930; 002205
  - Power, M,E. EST number of items = 5+. Including letters from family members regarding M.E. Powells death., 1947-1954; 002206
  - Prantl, Ferdinand. EST number of items = 5+., 1949-1953; 002207
  - Prausnitz, F.F. EST number of items = 1., 1950; 002208
  - Pribyl, Alois. EST number of items = 3., 1957; 002209
  - Pronin, G. EST number of items = 1., 002210
  - Pruitt, E.N. EST number of items = 2., 1952-1953; 002211
  - Pruvost, Pierre. EST number of items = 1., 1953; 002212
  - Raw, Frank. EST number of items = 5+., 1948-1950; 002213
  - Rehn, James. EST number of items = 1., 1952; 002214
  - Rehn, John. EST number of items = 1., 1949; 002215
  - Reimoser. EST number of items = 5+., 1913-1923; 002217
  - Reynolds, Paul. EST number of items = 1., 1963; 002216
  - Richards, H.G. EST number of items = 1., 1949; 002218
  - Richardson, E.S. EST number of items = 2., 1953; 002219
  - Richardson, Gladys. EST number of items = 1., 1948; 002220
  - Riel. EST number of items = 1., 1924; 002221
  - Ritchie, James. EST number of items = 10+., 1949-1953; 002222
  - Roger, Jean. EST number of items = 5+., 1949-1950; 002223
  - Roig, M.S. EST number of items = 2., 1920-1923; 002359
  - Roland Sala, J. EST number of items = 1., 1949; 002356
  - Rome. EST number of items = 1., 1953; 002224
  - Roofe, Paul G. EST number of items = 1., 1952; 002225
  - Root, H.S. EST number of items = 3., 1944; 002226
  - Rosas Costa, J. A. EST number of items = 5+., 1939-1946; 002227
  - Rose, H.G. EST number of items = 1., 1945; 002228
  - Rosenberg, D. EST number of items = 1., 1945; 002229
  - Rostoustegg. EST number of items = 1., 1936; 002230
  - Roth, V. D. EST number of items = 5., 1947-1950; 002231
  - Rousseau, J. EST number of items = 2., 1946; 002232
  - Roy, A.B. EST number of items =1., 1953; 002233
  - Royal Institute of Natural Science. EST number of items = 5+., 1949-1953; 002367
  - Royal Society of Edinburgh. EST number of items =3., 1949; 002234
  - Rust, F.N. EST number of items =2., 1917; 002235
  - Ryberg, Olof. EST number of items =1., 1917; 002236
  - Ryckman, R. E. EST number of items =2., 1953; 002237
  - Sachtler, Harry H. EST number of items = 1., 1931; 002238
  - Samuel, Sister Mary. EST number of items = 1., 1945; 002357
  - Saunders, F. EST number of items = 1., 1950; 002239
  - Savory T.H. EST number of items = 15+., 1924-1961; 002261
  - Sayce, R.U. EST number of items = 2., 1949; 002240
  - Scharrer, E. EST number of items = 2., 1930-1931; 002358
  - Schepler, H.C. EST number of items = 1., 002241
  - Schmidt, Gunter. EST number of items = 1., 1952; 002242
  - Schroeder, R.W. EST number of items = 2., 1945; 002246